=Destiny of the General's Bride=
=مصير عروس الجنرال=
=Episode 23=
=الحلقة 23=
Be careful
احرص
and don't break...
ولا تنكسر...
Why are you here, demoness?
لماذا أنت هنا أيها الشيطان؟
I should be asking you that.
ينبغي لي أن أسألك ذلك.
How can they touch General's belongings?
كيف يمكنهم لمس ممتلكات الجنرال؟
He's on death row,
إنه في انتظار تنفيذ حكم الإعدام
so he's no longer a general.
لذلك فهو لم يعد جنرالا.
And you.
وأنت.
I thought
اعتقدت
you loved each other in weal and woe.
لقد أحببتم بعضكم البعض في السراء والضراء.
Now
الآن
you're here saving your own skin.
أنت هنا لإنقاذ بشرتك.
General and I have agreed to have a divorce.
لقد اتفقنا أنا والجنرال على الطلاق.
And it's the deadline.
والآن هو الموعد النهائي.
Here's the repudiation letter.
وهنا رسالة الرفض.
Please pass it to him on my behalf.
من فضلك مرره له نيابة عني.
(Repudiation Letter)
(رسالة براءة)
Trying to cut ties with Xiao Yun
محاولة قطع العلاقات مع شياو يون
to get away with it?
للتخلص من ذلك؟
I won't let you get your way.
لن أسمح لك بتحقيق ما تريد.
Is he dead?
هل هو ميت؟
Not yet.
ليس بعد.
He's breathing his last.
إنه يتنفس آخر أنفاسه.
We've been waiting for you two.
لقد كنا في انتظاركما.
Wake him up with some water.
أيقظه ببعض الماء.
Let him see how his former lover
فلينظر كيف حبيبته السابقة
has treated him.
لقد عالجته.
You're losing it, huh?
أنت تخسرها، أليس كذلك؟
What my Ye had
ما كان لدي يي
was worse than these few whips you've had!
كان أسوأ من تلك السوطات القليلة التي حصلت عليها!
When he
عندما هو
was doing that to Hua,
كان يفعل ذلك مع هوا،
he should've seen that coming.
كان ينبغي له أن يتوقع ذلك.
How loyal you are.
كم أنت مخلص.
It's a shame that your Hua
من العار أن هوا الخاص بك
has run away.
لقد هرب.
I knew it, you're still alive.
لقد عرفت أنك لازلت على قيد الحياة.
You need not provoke me
لا داعي لاستفزازني
with such a lowly trick.
مع هذه الخدعة المتواضعة.
You don't believe it?
ألا تصدق ذلك؟
Then I'll show you
ثم سأريك
the repudiation letter she got you.
رسالة الرفض التي حصلت عليها منك.
"Xiao Yun, Grand General of 30,000 Calvary in Jiangzhou,
"شياو يون، الجنرال الكبير لـ 30.000 جلجثة في جيانغتشو،
is to be executed for a grave offense.
يجب تنفيذ الحكم عليه بالإعدام لارتكابه جريمة خطيرة.
His wife, Qing Yan, weeps as she bids farewell to him.
زوجته، تشينغ يان، تبكي وهي تودعه.
A chill wind blows, tears hard to stop.
تهب ريح باردة، والدموع يصعب إيقافها.
Petals fall without a sound, the heart already spent.
تتساقط البتلات دون صوت، والقلب منهك بالفعل.
She hereby sets down this letter of divorce,
وهي تضع بموجب هذا خطاب الطلاق هذا،
lest there be no proof hereafter.
لئلا يكون هناك دليل فيما بعد.
This written agreement shall serve as evidence."
"يعتبر هذا الاتفاق المكتوب بمثابة دليل."
Qing Yan...
تشينغ يان ...
Xiao Yun, what else do you have to say?
شياو يون، ماذا لديك لتقوله أيضًا؟
I've said
لقد قلت
what I needed to say.
ما كنت بحاجة إلى قوله.
Today's the third day.
اليوم هو اليوم الثالث.
Execute him.
أعدمه
Qing Yan.
تشينغ يان.
I fear I can't wait much longer.
أخشى أنني لا أستطيع الانتظار لفترة أطول.
Hold on!
يتمسك!
Her Highness...
صاحبة السمو...
Imperial Uncle, please put the execution on hold.
العم الإمبراطوري، من فضلك أوقف تنفيذ الإعدام.
It's a death sentence,
إنه حكم الإعدام
there's no way we're postponing it.
لا توجد طريقة لتأجيل ذلك.
Twenty years ago,
منذ عشرين عاما،
there was a concubine murder case at Xiao Residence.
كانت هناك قضية قتل محظية في منزل شياو.
General Xiao is the main witness of that case,
الجنرال شياو هو الشاهد الرئيسي في هذه القضية،
so he needs to be there to give his testimony.
لذلك فهو بحاجة إلى أن يكون هناك ليقدم شهادته.
That's a crime of passion among the common folk.
وهذه جريمة عاطفية بين عامة الناس.
What does that have to do with me?
ما علاقة هذا بي؟
Carry on with the execution.
واصل التنفيذ.
That woman was Mo Mei.
كانت تلك المرأة مو مي.
Stop!
قف!
Rest assured, Your Lordship.
اطمئن يا صاحب السعادة.
(Twenty years ago) I'll treat Mo Mei
(منذ عشرين عامًا) سأعالج مو مي
like how I treat my own wife.
مثلما أعامل زوجتي.
(Old General Xiao) When your son is born,
(الجنرال القديم شياو) عندما يولد ابنك،
I'll treat him like my own.
سأعامله كأنه ابني.
I won't let anyone bully them.
لن اسمح لأحد أن يتنمر عليهم.
The situation in court is complicated.
الوضع في المحكمة معقد.
I fear that me taking the wrong side
أخشى أن أتخذ الجانب الخطأ
will implicate Mo Mei.
سوف تورط مو مي.
Therefore, no one must know
لذلك لا يجب على أحد أن يعرف
about my relationship with Mo Mei.
عن علاقتي مع مو مي.
I understand.
أفهم.
Mo Mei is a woman I met while traveling.
مو مي هي امرأة التقيت بها أثناء السفر.
The child she carries is mine.
الطفل الذي تحمله هو طفلي.
It has nothing to do with Your Lordship.
لا علاقة لهذا الأمر بسيادتكم.
Honey, come and meet Mo Mei.
عزيزتي، تعالي للتعرف على مو مي.
From today on,
من اليوم فصاعدا،
she is your little sister.
إنها أختك الصغيرة.
(Madam Mo Mei)
(سيدتي مو مي)
(Heritage of Generations)
(تراث الأجيال)
Thank you, Your Highness.
شكرا لك يا صاحب السمو.
You'd better explain
من الأفضل أن تشرح
what you just said.
ما قلته للتو.
Your Lordship, don't believe their nonsense!
يا صاحب السعادة، لا تصدق هراءهم!
They've been bewitched by that demoness!
لقد تم سحرهم من قبل هذا الشيطان!
As for this case,
أما بالنسبة لهذه الحالة،
I already have an advocate.
لدي بالفعل محامي.
Please come in.
من فضلك ادخل.
Didn't...
لم...
Didn't you leave?
لم تغادر؟
Grand Madam Xiao,
السيدة الكبرى شياو،
you didn't truly think
لم تفكر حقا
I'd divorce General Xiao, did you?
هل تريدين الطلاق من الجنرال شياو؟
"A chill wind blows, tears hard to stop.
"تهب ريح باردة، والدموع يصعب إيقافها.
Petals fall without a sound, the heart already spent."
"تسقط البتلات دون صوت، والقلب منهك بالفعل."
That was clearly my signal to him.
لقد كانت هذه بوضوح إشارتي له.
That pendant...
هذه القلادة...
Where did you get it?
من أين حصلت عليه؟
Your Lordship, it's a long story.
سيدي، إنها قصة طويلة.
Please
لو سمحت
hear me out.
اسمعني.
(Your Lordship used to)
(سيادتكم اعتادوا على ذلك)
(have a lover who was an ordinary folk.)
(لدي حبيب كان من عامة الناس.)
Your Lordship!
سيادتكم!
(Her name was Mo Mei.)
(كان اسمها مو مي.)
You're back.
لقد عدت.
Have you thought of a name
هل فكرت في اسم؟
for our child?
من أجل طفلنا؟
You'll know on the day he's born.
ستعرف ذلك في اليوم الذي يولد فيه.
(But with the turmoil of the times,)
(ولكن مع اضطرابات العصر)
(you feared she might be implicated.)
(كنت خائفة من تورطها.)
(Thus, he entrusted her to Old General Xiao)
(وهكذا، عهد بها إلى الجنرال العجوز شياو)
(and strictly ordered her identity kept secret.)
(وأمرت بشدة بالحفاظ على هويتها سرية.)
(But then war suddenly broke out)
(ولكن فجأة اندلعت الحرب)
(and Old General Xiao died in battle.)
(و مات الجنرال العجوز شياو في المعركة.)
(And Mo Mei passed away from illness.)
(وتوفي مو مي بسبب المرض.)
But what you didn't know was
ولكن ما لم تعرفه هو
Mo Mei did not die of plague.
لم تمت مو مي بالطاعون.
She was killed by Grand Madam Xiao.
لقد تم قتلها على يد السيدة الكبرى شياو.
You've got better
لقد أصبحت أفضل
at making up stories.
في اختلاق القصص.
Then tell me.
ثم أخبرني
What proof do you have?
ما هو الدليل الذي لديك؟
Due to her jealousy,
بسبب غيرتها،
ever since Mo Mei entered the Xiao Residence,
منذ أن دخلت مو مي مقر إقامة شياو،
Grand Madam Xiao made things hard for her and the child.
السيدة الكبرى شياو جعلت الأمور صعبة عليها وعلى الطفل.
She even told me to kill the young heir.
حتى أنها طلبت مني أن أقتل الوريث الشاب.
But he was still so small.
ولكنه كان لا يزال صغيرا جدا.
(I couldn't bring myself to do that.)
(لم أستطع أن أجبر نفسي على فعل ذلك.)
(Later,)
(لاحقاً،)
(Grand Madam Xiao ordered me to kill Madam Mo Mei.)
(أمرتني السيدة الكبرى شياو بقتل السيدة مو مي.)
She threatened me
لقد هددتني
to make my husband divorce me if I refused to do that.
أن أجعل زوجي يطلقني إذا رفضت ذلك.
Everything has been seen to.
لقد تم رؤية كل شيء.
And Xiao Yun?
وشياو يون؟
He lost his mother and fell into a high fever.
لقد فقد أمه وأصيب بحمى شديدة.
His days are numbered.
أيامه معدودة.
Madam.
سيدتي.
The King of Xiling is here.
ملك شيلينغ هنا.
He's asking to see Mo Mei.
إنه يطلب رؤية مو مي.
Who?
من؟
Second Madam, Mo Mei.
السيدة الثانية، مو مي.
(Only then did Grand Madam Xiao realize)
(حينها فقط أدركت السيدة الكبرى شياو)
(Mo Mei was Your Lordship's woman.)
(مو مي كانت امرأة سيادتك.)
We... We'll just say Mo Mei passed away
نحن... سنقول فقط أن مو مي توفيت
from fatigue after childbirth and longing for him.
من تعب الولادة والشوق إليه.
Then we return Xiao Yun to His Lordship.
ثم نعيد شياو يون إلى سيده.
You fool! Xiao Yun has grown up.
يا أحمق! شياو يون قد كبر.
If he blurts out in His Lordship's presence
إذا تفوه في حضور صاحب السيادة
that we abused
أننا أساءنا معاملتنا
and poisoned his mother,
وسمم أمه،
would we get away with it?
هل سننجو من ذلك؟
Well...
حسنًا...
Our only choice
خيارنا الوحيد
is to tell His Lordship
هو أن يخبر سيادته
that Ye is his child.
أن يي هو ابنه.
But...
لكن...
But I don't think that's appropriate.
ولكنني لا أعتقد أن هذا مناسب.
Didn't you want a position
ألم ترغب في الحصول على منصب؟
for your husband?
لزوجك؟
Now's the chance.
الآن هي الفرصة.
Will you take it or not?
هل ستأخذه أم لا؟
And so
وهكذا
she tricked Your Lordship
لقد خدعت سيادتك
into acknowledging Xiao Ye as your son.
في الاعتراف بأن شياو يي هو ابنك.
Utter nonsense!
هذا هراء تماما!
How can we trust
كيف يمكننا أن نثق
these woman and servant?
هذه المرأة والخادمة؟
Your Lordship, please exercise your judgment!
سيدي الرئيس، من فضلك استخدم حكمك!
This is the proof.
وهذا هو الدليل.
This pendant was given by General Xiao's mother.
تم إهداء هذه القلادة من قبل والدة الجنرال شياو.
He has always worn it.
لقد ارتداه دائمًا.
It's an ordinary trinket.
إنها مجرد تحفة عادية.
How can you prove it was Mo Mei's?
كيف يمكنك إثبات أنها كانت لمو مي؟
On its own, this jade pendant
بحد ذاته، هذه القلادة اليشمية
seems nothing special.
يبدو أنه لا يوجد شيء خاص.
But paired with Your Lordship's plum blossom pendant,
ولكن مع قلادة زهرة البرقوق الخاصة بسيادتك ،
it's clear this was the token of love between you and Mo Mei.
من الواضح أن هذا كان رمزًا للحب بينك وبين مو مي.
Madam Xiao.
السيدة شياو.
Is Qing Yan
هل تشينغ يان
telling the truth?
قول الحقيقة؟
Xiao Yun
شياو يون
is indeed Your Lordship's son.
إنه في الواقع ابن سيادتكم.
♪Mountains and rivers rise and fall♪
???الجبال والأنهار ترتفع وتنخفض؟؟؟
♪The vast sea opens wide♪
???البحر الواسع ينفتح على مصراعيه؟؟؟
♪Thank you for staying with me♪
شكرا لك على البقاء معي؟؟؟
♪To witness all the lights of the world♪
???لرؤية جميع أضواء العالم؟؟؟
♪I remember by the old tree in Qing Yan♪
???أتذكر بجانب الشجرة القديمة في تشينغ يان؟؟؟
♪When we first met♪
???عندما التقينا لأول مرة؟؟؟
♪Looking back, no more words are needed♪
???بالنظر إلى الوراء، لم تعد هناك حاجة إلى المزيد من الكلمات؟؟؟
♪You went left, I went right♪
???أنت ذهبت إلى اليسار، وأنا ذهبت إلى اليمين؟؟؟
♪If we hadn't met, there'd be nothing to seek♪
???لو لم نلتقي فلن يكون هناك ما نبحث عنه؟؟؟
♪In this long, dusty road of life♪
في هذا الطريق الطويل والمترب من الحياة؟؟؟
♪Love and hate poured in a single jar of wine♪
???الحب والكراهية سكبوا في جرة واحدة من النبيذ ???
♪Whose heart does love truly claim♪
من يملك قلب الحب الحقيقي؟؟؟
♪Yet it yields to just one greeting♪
???ومع ذلك فإنه يستجيب لتحية واحدة فقط؟؟؟
♪Gentle longing flows into the river♪
???شوق لطيف يتدفق في النهر؟؟؟
♪When dreams break, we will guard each other still♪
???عندما تتحطم الأحلام، هل سنحمي بعضنا البعض أيضًا؟؟؟